<excerpts>
  <chan_laisun>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-04-28" Title="Address at Hartford" Page="3">It looks peculiar for one of another nation, dressed in another costume, to speak before an intelligent audience like this like this in an intelligent manner. It is twenty five years since I have been in this country; so if I seem rather rusty in my English, and make some mistakes, you will attribute it to rustiness and not to want of ability. What are we here tonight for? For education!  It is education among the people that elevates a nation. I am not going to give you an eloquent address tonight on this subject; but I will endeavor to compare our system of education with yours. Our system is a general one, as is yours. The Chinaman that can afford it will send his boy to school; and no matter how poor he may be, he can, if he is competent, reach the chair of the prime minister. It is not confined to any particular class, but is free and common to all. The same system that existed there 8000 years ago exists today. Every town in China has its school, every city its high school, and each province its university. Our system is as democratic as yours. Yours is producing the greatest result. Why, education fairly makes my hair stand! Where is the nation highly educated that is not highly civilized? Look at the United States, at England Prussia. We have a saying in China, “This day the flower blooms, and behold it is another year.” Your career is just begun. Whatever your future destiny may be, do your best! </text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-02-27" Title="Arts and Sciences in China" Page="3">China, once boasted the proudest civilization and her ingenuities were even now the wonder,if not the admirations of the world. Nearly all the great inventions now traced their origin to a nation truly ancient. Porcelain was common in China as early as 165 B.C., and attained its greatest perfection 1000 years ago, while porcelain ornaments have been discovered which dated back 12 centuries before the Christian era. China-ware was common in Europe while China itself was yet unknown. Then came the Dutch navigators, who for long years supplied all Europe with this ware, till the taste for it grew to a passion, and fabulons sums were offered for simple specimens at ancient porcelain. The finest pure white porcelain was the product of the Tokain kiln, and was in the shape of cups and ornaments, with devices under the glaze which were only seen when held up to the light. This kiln was now destroyed, and its beautiful porcelain was very rare. The blue and white porcelain was made at Nankeen until the Tai Ping rebels took the city in 1852. The only considerable porcelain manufactory in China at the present time is at Jingdezhen on Poyang lake. Inferior porcelain was made at many places but nothing that could compare with the work of former days. The discovery of the much-prized crackled China was was purely accidental. Two brothers who manufactured porcelain once quarreled and separated, each setting up for himself. One night, through ill-will, one of them poured cold water in this brother’s kiln, which was filled with porcelain still hot, but instead of being ruined, as was intended, it came out crackled porcelain and made its owner rich. All porcelain was made from a clay or mineral called kaolin, which was flexible, infusible, and of a pure white color bordering on flesh red. The kaolin was found in mountains, amid blocks of granite, and that of China and Japan was whiter than the European article. When agglutinated by the addition of feldspar and fired, or baked. It became semi-transparent. The uses of kaolin were almost universal. Household utensils, roof tiles, flooring slabs were all formed from it. But the greatest monument of porcelaining was the Nankeen tower, which was built of solid porcelain pricks, when nankeen was the capital, 800 years ago. Its walls, glistening in the sum, were visible for miles and it stood for ages, the pride of Nankeen, until destroyed by a rebel fanatic in 1852. The art of enameling in gold, silver and copper was also of very ancient date, and was carried to a high state of perfection. Everything could be enameled. The different colors were obtained by mixing them with the kaolin before the porcelain was made. The art of printing was known in china 3000 years ago, and the practice of printing on paper from chiseled blocks was practiced now as then. The characters were written on thin paper and plastered face downward on the block. Then it was gently worked with the finger till the paper was removed and the characters remained. Then the wood was cut away and the characters left in relief. The printing was done wholly by hand. First the printer inled the letters with a brush, at the same time reaching with his left hand for the paper. With a single motion the paper was laid across the block and a few rubs with a dry brush completed the operation. An expert printer struck off from 8000 to 10,000 impressions daily/ The whole of the Chinese language has however been printed from moveable types. Copied from the Europeans. Books in China were not dear, and all the standard histories and school books were very cheap. The whole of the Confucian classics were sold at from 30 cents to $1.50, according to the quality of the paper, while the Chinese primer, containing 1086 characters, sold from 1 to 2 cents per copy. The Chinese never laid duties on books. Although the invention of gunpowder was claimed by both Germany and England, yet incendiary projectiles were known in China 300 or 400 years B.C., while Grecian historians relate how the progress of Alexander was barred near the Ganges because the gods of the country shot thunder and lightning. The chief feature of Chinese gunpowder was the larger amount of sulphur used in its composition. The mariner’s compass was also invented by a Chinaman, 4000 years ago. The Chinese called it a needle pointing to the south, because it was the height of disloyalty to say pointing to the north, which place was worshiped by Chinese as the dwelling-place of their ruler, and because the Chinaman was opposite to everyone. But the Chinese have regarded this useful instrument as the prototype of the cold north star, and though extensive navigators have relied on it but little.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-01-15" Title="Chan Lai Sun Questions a Characteristic of our Civilization" Page="8">On Monday afternoon, as I was taking my usual walk up State Street, when nearly midway of the sidewalk belonging to the armory grounds, a fellow with another man in a sleigh was riding down the hill, saw me walking, and without the least provocation, sing out, “See that d-d Chinaman,” And then he finished off with “Can ma-Kee?” addressing me. I stood there, perfectly astounded at this strange way of salutation, and followed him with my eyes as he rode away. I looked around to see if there were any policeman, to get him to give me an introduction to the braggadocio, but could see none. May I venture to ask you, sir, as a public teacher, what punishment does the law of your country inflict upon such person, who uses abusive language without provocation, at the representative of a foreign government? In my country –  China –  we hold such men as sacred, and if any abuse of whatever nature be practiced on them by any of our subjects, he is flogged within an inch of his life, and then is obliged to carry a piece of board on his shoulder called the Cangue, and exposed to public view. It may be that this is not your mode of punishment for such crime; but probably you will be pleased to inform the fellow, who may read your wide-circulated paper, the penalty of his salutation if ever I put him through a course of sprouts. I am, sir, yours, A STRANGER IN A STRANGE LAND.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-10-09" Title="Chinese Agriculture" Page="5">About two thousand years before the Christian era, the Chinese tribe first settled in the land now known as the province of Shensi, where they increased so greatly until they spread and occupied the whole Eighteen Provinces, which is now called China Proper. The tribe remained a short time in the province of Shensi, the cradle of the Chinese Empire, consolidating strength under their patriarchal chieftains, and gradually pushes themselves at every point of the compass, fighting against physical difficulties of the country. This people brought with them habits of settled labor, and an amount of civilization far superior to those who had preceded them, and thus they were able to subdue the land, and replenish it. History shows that no sooner they were settled down in their new acquired territory than the arts of agriculture and the weaving were displayed. The cultivation of grain for food and flax for clothing were the first objects of their solicitude. Silkworms and mulberry trees were highly appreciated, and great care was bestowed to the rearing of them. It is said the Chinese were clothed with silk long before they had any knowledge of cotton. This valuable plant was introduced into China about 600 years ago from India. In addition to these endowments, the early Chinese possessed the element of intellectual culture. They had a slight knowledge of astronomy; new approximately the length of the year, and recognized the necessity of an intercalary months once every three years, to adjust the seasons, on which their process of agriculture depended. They possessed the elements of their present written hieroglyphical language. end as early as the beginning of Shang Dynasty, B. C. 1765, one of the ministers of state presented a written memorial to his sovereign. With these superior endowments of mind, and the various elements of strength flowing from it, they have carried their civilization, boats in the culture of the mind as well of the soil, two such height, vet, and one period of the world’s history, China stood far above any other nation, and even to this day some of her arts and sciences are not superseded. It is not our province to say much at this time the Chinese elements of intellectual culture. but I wish to bring before you the industrial art of the people whose energies have been exerted for thousands of the year in forcing the earth to yield its products to the support of a redundant population. Among the various branches of labor, agriculture holds the highest place in the estimation of the people. To make this labor honorable, the sovereign sets the example by appearing in person, early in spring, on the sacred field, and, with a highly ornamented plow drawn by an ox, he turns over three furrows, the princess of the royal blood five furrows, and, lastly, the high ministers of state nine furrows. This being done, the emperor and his ministers repair to a pavilion and remain there until the whole field is plowed. The ceremony is of very ancient date, and takes place on the ground of the temple dedicated to heaven and earth at the capital of the empire. This crop raised by his imperial majesty is especially consecrated to the use of the Gods. At this ceremony, a big ox made of clay, with the number of little ones, are carried in a procession to the sacred field. After the field is ploughed, these clay images are broken into pieces, and the multitude scramble for the broken bits, and scatter the ashes over their field to insure an auspicious harvest. Throughout the provinces of the empire, civilians of high and low degree are also required to perform the same ceremony on the same day. Here the prefect and others, having tamed the sod with the plough, return home; on the second day, they meet at early dawn in a temple dedicated to the god of grain, offer sacrifices, and repeat prayers, and perform a series of prostration. As soon as this religious rite is over, at a given signal the clay ox receives a blow at this forehead, when the crowd rushes to secure a piece of the image to strew on their fields. All lands are held as freehold as long as the government receives its annual rent, either in specie or in kind, which is about one-tenth part of its produce. Owing to the redundant population, very few farmers own more than two or three hundred acres. Some, indeed, own their exceptional cases. But millions and millions of them own ten or twenty acres. Thus, the Chinese are considered by Europeans more like gardeners than farmers. The plains of the middle and southern provinces are made to yield two to three crops in rotation every year; at the north, only two. But when patches are laid out for raising vegetables, five, six, seven, and even eight crops are realized. The principal staples of production are: Rice, tea, silk, cotton, hemp (which Chinese make into grass cloth for dresses, of which there are three species, known by the botanical names of Cannabis sativa, Sida titiafolia, Netica nivea), tobacco, indigo, sugar-cane, camphor, vegetable wax, bamboo, from which all paper is made, sweet and Irish potatoes, both foreign plants introduced into the country, the latter solely for European use. Our limited time will not permit us to go into details of the various manipulations of tea, silk, cotton and hemp—a species of flax. We all are aware of the great benefit these have conferred upon mankind throughout the world. We are sure that tea and silk can be made to grow upon American soil, especially in the regions of California, Texas, Arizona and New Mexico; but before you can afford to sell tea at ten or twelve cents a pound, it is useless to make an attempt. Tobacco is raised in great quantity, and some of very superior quality. It is smoked in pipes, very little being made into cigars ; chewing is unknown. Nor have the Chinese arrived to that high state of civilization as to use the juice of this weed in daubing the beautiful silk dresses of the fair ladies. The sugar-cane is principally raised in the southern provinces. Substitute manual labor for steam, the process of making sugar is the same in both countries, with this exception: the Chinese do not purify it with ox’s blood, but press it with mud. It has not that crystalline appearance as the sugar made in this country. Camphor-trees grow in immense forests, and are of great height and dimensions. The process of making camphor is like that of making maple-sugar from the mapletree. The vegetable wax, which we get from the tallow-tree (Stitlingia sebifera), is a tree grown over all the eastern part of China and some parts of the provinces bordering on Thibet and Burinah. An English traveller, describing it, says: “It is a beautiful tree, resembling the aspen in its shape and foliage ; it would form a valuable addition to the list of shade trees in this country. The seeds grow in clusters like ivy berries, and are collected in November ; when ripe the capsule divides, and, falling off, discovers two or three kernels covered with pure white tallow. When the tallow is to be prepared, these are picked from the stalks and put into an open wooden cylinder with a perforated bottom, in which they are well steamed over boiling-water. In ten or fifteen minutes the tal low covering the seeds becomes soft, and they are then thrown into a stone mortar and gently beaten with mallets to detach it. The whole is then sifted on a hot sieve, by which the tallow is separated from the kernels, though containing the brown skin which envelops the latter, and presenting a dirty appear ance. The tallow in this state is inclosed in a straw cylinder, or laid upon layers of straw, held together by iron hoops, and subjected to pressure in a rude press, from which it runs clear in a semi-fluid state, and soon hardens, into cakes. The candles made from it become soft in hot weather, and are sometimes coated by dipping them in wax.” The bamboo plant is cultivated almost everywhere; it is remarkable for its shade and beauty. There are about sixty varieties, different in size, according to its genus ; ranging from that of a switch to a big pole, measuring from four to five inches in diameter. It is reared from shoots and suckers, and, after the root once clings to the ground, it thrives and spreads without further care or labor. Of these sixty varieties, each thrives best in a certain locality. And throughout the whole empire of China the bamboo groves not only embellish the gardens of the poor, but the vast parks of the princes and wealthy. The use to which this stately grass i3 put is truly wonderful. The tender shoots are cultivated for food like the asparagus ; the roots are carved into fantastic images of men, birds, and monkeys. The tapering culms are used for all purposes that poles can be applied to, – in carrying, supporting, propelling, and measuring ; by the porter, the carpenter and the boatman ; for the joists of houses and the ribs of sails ; the shafts of spears and the wattles of hurdles ; the tubes of aqueducts and the handles and ribs of umbrellas and fans. The leaves are sewed upon cords to make rain-cloaks for farmers and boatmen, for sails to boats as well as junks, swept into heaps to form manure, and matted into thatches to cover houses. The bamboo wood is cut into splints and slivers of various sizes to make into baskets and trays of every form and fancy, twisted into cables, plaited into awnings, and woven into mats for the bed and floor, for the sceneries of the theatre, for the roofs of boats, and the casing of goods. The shavings are picked into oakum to be stuffed into mattresses. The bamboo furnishes the bed for sleeping and the couch for reclining, the chair for sitting, the chopsticks for eating, the pipe for smoking, the flute for entertaining ; a curtain to hang before the door, and a broom to sweep around it. The ferule to govern the scholar, the book he studies and the paper he writes upon, all originated from this wonderful grass. The tapering barrels of the organ and the dreadful instrument of the lictor,—one to strike harmony and the other to strike dread ; the rule to measure lengths, the cup to gauge quantities, and the bucket to draw water;' the bellows to blow the fire and the box to retain the match ; the bird-cage and crab-not, the fish-pole, the water-wheel and eave-duct, wheelbarrow and handcart, aud a host of other things, are the utilities to which this magnificent grass is converted. I therefore highly recommend this most useful of grasses to your consideration. The agricultural tools of a Chinese farmer are simple and primitive, being the same as those used for thousands of years past. The plough and the harrow are used for cultivating rice and other grains, while the hoe, spade, shovel and mattocks are used for gardening. The plough is made of wood, the share of which is edged with iron, very flat, aud does not penetrate into the ground more than five or six inches. The harrow is a triangular wood frame, interlined with slabs three inches square, with wooden or iron spikes, two or three inches long, sticking out ou one side, and the driver stands on the other side while harrowing. The hoe is used for gardening purposes. The edge of the wooden blade is guarded with iron, giving weight and impetus to its blow. The deficiency of tools is made up by patient and hard labor. The strain put upon the soil to yield so many crops beyond the limits of nature must necessitate the enormous use of manure. Here the Chinese are not at their wit's end. The practice of ages comes to their assistance. Night-soil from all cities and towns is collected into reservoirs; refuse is gathered from the sweepings of houses ; poor men and boys may be seen all day long, from the earliest morn, sweeping the streets, paths and fields, gathering the excrements of pigs, dogs, cows and horses. Some make a specialty of collecting offal and bones. A great number are employed in scooping the weeds from the beds of canals, ponds, lakes and rivers, which are put into vats, and covered with mud, to cause them to rot. After oil is pressed from the beans, the bean-cakes are used for manure. The quality and strength of the manure is used according to the requirements of the soil and plant. Rotten fish is also used for this purpose. Almost all kinds of vegetables raised in this country are raised in China. There is a certain winter vegetable which thrives best when the frost is thick and snow abundant. Fruits, melons and grapes abound. In the northern provinces, watermelons are so abundant that one entering their fields can eat all the melons he wishes, if he will only leave the seeds. These seeds are sent throughout the country in shiploads. Peaches are fine, better than any I have tasted here. The natives cook them in brine, and then parch them on iron pans. In the southern provinces oranges and other tropical fruits are raised, some of which are not known in this country, such as the Itches, lung gans, curambola and pomelots. Oranges are often sold on the spot at fifty to seventy cents per bushel. But further north, two to four dollars are paid per bushel. Rearing of horses is entirely confined to the northern provinces. The horse commonly seen there is more like a Shetland pony. It is bony and strong. The improvement of this noble animal is entirely neglected, and he looks sorry enough compared with the coursers of India or Persia. He is principally used for carrying the post or for military services. Asses and mules arc more employed for draught in the northeastern province, and camels in Central Asia. In the southern provinces this animal is scarce, owing to the country being cut up with many canals. Sheep are raised in the northern and middle provinces. Their wool is used for making felt, and their meat is much eaten. Cattle are raised throughout the empire. The southern Chinese seldom use (eat) beef on account of religious scruples. They cannot bear to eat the flesh of the animal which had helped the farmer to till the soil to raise grain for the support of man. But the northern ers use it freely. There is an animal called the buffalo, very hardy and strong. It resembles the ox, almost hairless ; its color is black. It is an animal I would strongly advise you to introduce, not for the delicacy of its flesh, but for its power in tilling the soil and heavy draught. A buffalo has two or three times the strength of a horse, and is more steady. Compared with an ox, I should think the buffalo is the stronger of the two. We can readily see the raising of domestic animals is so much neglected for the want of pastoral lands. Grain is too clear to allow acres of land to lie idle for the sake of its grass. The Chinese pig has short legs, round body, sloping back and very short and pug nose. It takes very little to raise them, and pork is the most common meat in the empire. The black Chinese breed, as it is called in England, where it is introduced, is considered the best pork raised in that country. Chickens of the Cochin tribe, and ducks almost as large as geese, are common domestic fowls. The former have been introduced into this country, but I have not seen the duck.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-06-16" Title="First Church Sunday School Anniversary" Page="2">﻿That old religious forms were not ready to give up their hold upon the hearts of the people, and before many years I predicted fearful prosecution. But from the blood of the murdered would rise Christianity in its strength and glory, and a civilization of the Bible so become worldwide.</text>
    <text Source="Eleventh Report of the Commissioner on Fisheries of the State of Connecticut" Date="1877-01" Title="Fish Culture in China" Page="18 - 19">﻿That fish culture in China is a part of the business of agriculture. Every man who owns a piece of land where water can be held, stocks it with fish, the better qualities for eating, and the coarser kinds for fertilising the soil: they grow so large and are so prolific as to furnish the farmer a large proportion of his manures for crops especially requiring phosphates.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-02-15" Title="Marriage in China" Page="4">Indeed, the theory that prevails in China respecting the organ from which our wisdom or knowledge comes is very different from the one that Americans hold. The latter locate the mind in the brain, while we suppose it to be in the stomach. This may be because the two countries are bound to hold contrary view. It would probably take me about three months to tell you all about the customs and manners of the country from which I came, so I will confine myself to one subject, – the Chinese marriage ceremony. The young man who wants to marry, but is bashful, had better go to China. There the work will all be done for him by a go-between. A professional matchmaker will manage the entire negotiation for $10 or $20. But the ladies would find it unpleasant there, for they have no voice in the matter. When a son is approaching manhood – say at the age of 16 or 18 – his parents begin to look up a suitable person to become his wife. The services of a matchmaker are secured, and she (for a person of this profession is almost invariably a woman) recommends some maiden as a fitting person. She deliates on the charms and excellences of the girl, describes her feet, two inches and a half long, and her delicate hands, and, in general, makes her appear as well as possible. The mother, after consulting the almanac and selecting a lucky day, mounts ger sedan chair and goes to the house of the young lady, some intimations of her visit having been previously sent. She is received by servants in a sitting-hall, where she smokes her pipe, if she chances to be a user of the weed. A cup of tea is brought, and she is always expected to take at least a sip of it. The maiden, when presented, is the object of the closest scrutiny, which, however, always ends in compliments upon her feet, hands and other members. The finger-nails are important as beautiful features. They are often three inches in length; frequently, too, the are plated with gold or silver, both for purpose of adornment and to present them from being broken. The mother obtains a history of the young lady’s life, writes out the horoscope of her son and both accounts are place before the household god. Not infrequently she consults a soothsayer who is familiar with the science of astrology. The signs of the zodiac are represented in China by animals, not the same ones, however, that we use. If one of the prospective parties to the contract is born under the sign of the tiger, and the other under that of the rat, the mother in great consternation suggests that the tiger may eat up the rat, and there will be a fuss in the family; but the soothsayer is paid for doing his work, and he usually contrives to explain away the unpropitious signs, and gets his fee of 50 cents or less. So far, so good. The youth sends a beautiful present to the damsel, accompanied by a slip of paper bearing simply a word which means “beseech.” The maid, in turn, makes him the recipient of a gift, and sends with it the expression “I grant.” Up to this time, the work is merely preliminary. The parties, who very likely have never seen each other, may have to wait years for the consummation of their happiness. Sometimes betrothals are made before the birth of the persons. If both of the expected children are males, or both females – why, then the wedding never comes off. Just before the time set apart for a wedding-ceremony, a grand house-cleaning takes place. A great deal of money is spent on preparations; it costs the Chinese a round sum to marry or to die. Apart of the preparatory ceremony is the assembling, at the house of the betrothed maiden, of her intimate friends, who bewail her approaching departure into matrimony. The bribe usually does to the home of the groom. She is followed by a long procession, that marches to the sound of the drums, tom-toms and other musical instruments. The expenses of such a progress often amount to $80,000 or $40,000. The bride’s face is conceal by a red veil; and the hole procession is decked with red, for this color is symbolic of chastity. A lantern carried aloft bears the names, for example, of Ching and Chang, and indicates that Mr. Ching is about to marry Miss Chang. Anybody, even the highest official, who meets the procession, must turn out and let it pass. The bride, the groom and their friends meet around an altar erected at the house which they have now reached. On such an occasion as this alone can anybody, expect the emperor, worship God directly. Him they adore around the altar by kneeling three times and knocking their heads nine times against the floor. After that they worship the ancestors. Then the bride and groom go to a table, where a cup of wine is set before each, the cups being united by a cord. Here the happy man lifts the veil (he alone has power to do it) and looks upon his lady for the first time. But it is a long while before the relations of man and wife become intimate. They take no bridal tour, have no honeymoon; and the woman affects great shyness towards her lord. Such a ceremony as this, said the speaker, seems very strange to Americans, but it is justifiable, and even necessary, in the present semi-civilized condition of China. The rules of the society keep men and women widely separated. But, though concubinage prevails widely in China, chastity is a prominent virtue of the women of that country; and, on the whole, the marriage system of China is preferable to that of France and Austria.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-06-07" Title="Opium Trade and its Effects on China" Page="4">The history of commerce has seldom a darker page than is shown in the intercourse of these companies with the eastern nations. Among the early staples of trade, no article, whether of import or export, showed healthier statistics or a greater demand than opium. The introduction of opium into China dates from 1676, it being used for medical purposes. From a few tens of chests it grew to a thousand, and from this to 76,500 chests in 1856; in 1870. The amount consumed was over 150,000 chests, and every ounce of this was smoked by the Chinese. The drug is called in China a pien, imitation of opium; other vile names are given to it, Black Earth, Black Rice, Black Commodity, Smoking Dirt, Foreign Poison and Foreign Medicine. The opium is imported from India,and is produced from the fruit of the poppy; it is of two kinds, named from the provinces whence it is brough; the Patna weighs 160 pounds, and the Malwa 140 per chest. The Patna is warranted, and comes in balls resembling cannon balls; the Malwa is made by the people, and comes in chunks, and is liable to be impure. The revenue collected by the Indian government on opium in 1856-7 was nearly £4,000,000 sterling; in 1870-1 it was £8,000,000 sterling. It first dissolved in water, strained and boiled to a paste, then it is spread out like a very large pancake and left for several hours to soak; it is then boiled again until it becomes like thick treacle, when it is ready for use. The opium-pipe is similar to a flute, made of wood, bamboo or cane, with a bowl of earthenware at one extremity having a hole like a pin’s head. The smoker lies down on a couch, – never as he is often represented standing or sitting – having a small lamp well like by his side; he dips a needle like a knitting-needle into a small cup of the opium, and holds it over the lamp. When the stuff begins to swell he works it over on the bowl of his pipe, repeating the process until he has obtained a particle of opium the size of a pea, when he sticks it over the hole of his pipe and inhales five or six whiffs. Of the opium thus obtained three-tents evaporates in smoke and seven-tenths s lodged in the cavity of the bowl, which cavity is scraped now and then with a peculiar scraper. A novice is content with three or four pipes, which always produce nansea, vertigo and excitement, preventing sleep for hours. But an old smoker would draw with one breath the whole smoke of one pipe, allowing none to escape. The temperate smoker generally smokes after his meal, but the adept smokes at any and all times, especially at night. It is a notorious fact that the smoker of the black dirt while preparing the does with the needle over the the lamp, is brooding dark schemes of burglary and murder. The poor commit offenses of various degrees; but it is the high class of smokers among the mandarin officers, among lawyers, who spent their lives in the perpetration of the most horrid crimes and abominations that blacken the history of modern China. It is a byword among the Chinese that an opium-smoker is never to be trusted. The testimony given by men of all classes, merchants, missionaries, Europeans, opium dealers themselves being the judges, shows that the baleful effects of this drug upon the human systems are, the general deterioration of all the mental faculties, debility, sallow complexion, lividness of lips and eyelids, languor, lack of luster in the eye and hollowness of the voice. When the periodical thirst comes on, mucus flows from the nostrils, and tears from the eyes; the burning sensation in the throat cannot be allayed until the portions is administered. If the pipe is withheld altogether, coldness and aching pains penetrate the body, accompanied with diarrhea, and death finally ensues. There is not the least evidence that the court at Pekin was not sincere in its desire to suppress the trade from the first edict, in 1800, till the war broke out in 1840. The excuse that the government smuggled, because its revenue cruisers engaged in it, and the provincial authorities winked at it, is no more satisfactory, in a large view of the case, than is the successful bribery of custom house officers in England or elsewhere a proof of the corruption of the treasury department. The temptation of an increasing and lucrative trade was as strong in the heathen Chinee smuggler as it was to the Christian merchants and monopolists who placed the poisonous drug constantly within their reach. A treaty of peace was concluded, though the British government failed to induce the Chinese to legalize opium. The emperor said: “It is true, I cannot prevent the introduction of the flowing poison. Gain-seeking and corrupt men will, for profit and sensuality, defeat my wishes; but nothing will induce me to derive a revenue from the vice and misery of my people” O! Ye philanthropists of Christendom and ye friends of humanity, ye who have breathed the dungeon’s pestilential air, ye who have sacrificed millions of dollars to liberate the slaves, yea, ye who have given up your sons and your husbands to pour out their precious blood upon the altar of humanity, is it less meritorious to deliver a nation from the poison that sweeps them by millions to destruction, every year, through the perfidy of people boasting of Christian civilization and high culture? Shall the fleet of Great Britain keep pouring in year by year the deadly instrument, demoralizing the people, compared with which slavery is a blessing? Shall we see these destructive balls of opium wrapped with the leaves of the Bible presented to the poor Chinaman and say to them, “Read, digest and obtain eternal death?” Shall all the institutions of Christian benevolence to proclaim faith, hope and charity be made as dung-hills by Black Dirt? There are many men of pure mind in England, who from time to time denounce the diabolical traffic of opium in China, but they are not aware of the wholesale destruction committed in that country. Finally, you citizens of the United States, I appeal to your philanthropy, I appeal to your independence, shall the curse of the opium be the watchword of China’s salvation?</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-01-16" Title="Tea in China" Page="4">Tea grows in every Province in China, except three or four upon the northernmost Siberian border,But the quality and quantity produced depends largely upon locality. The tea-plant grows five or six feet high, and is like our currant shrub, only a little thicker. The leaves are in shape and size like those of the willow. They are picked about the middle of April, in May, and in July; sometimes there are gleanings as late as August. The leaves are not picked one by one, but stripped off in handful by men, women and children, who to go about doing this work.There are very few large tea plantations; is rare even to find one of a hundred acres, but there are tea patches everywhere. The real business of the country people is raising rice for food, but they cultivate tea and silk as extras, and for pocket-money, as the Irishman raises a pig. When the leaves are stripped off, they are exposed in a cool, dry place, for a day or two, then rolled into a ball on the table of bamboo slats, and dried in the sun. The rolling is to extract a portion of the juice of the leaves. After they have been dried in the sun, they are put into an egg-shaped iron pan over a charcoal fire, and incessantly stirred until a certain point of dryness is reached. The operator stirs with his hands, thrusting them in all portions of the pan, and practice enables him to dry the leaves almost exactly alike. The raiser goes through this process, and then bring his tea in bamboo baskets to the tea merchant, who adjudges its quality and buys it at prices varying from $15 to $20 per pien, equal 188 1-3 pounds. The merchant mixes his purchases together in a large reservoir, and at his convenience weighs out a number of pounds of tea leaves, and the women and children spread them upon a large stage and separate the leaves into grades, according to the quality. The tea stalks are the lowest grade, and the sorters are paid by the number of ounces of stalks they bring in. Children learn from four to five cents a day; the very best workers really earn as much as ten cents a day. Americans could hardly live upon such wages, and until other nations can raise for tea 12 cents a pound they cannot compete with China and its production. After the sorting, each grade is packed by itself in chest or bamboo baskets; the first for exportation, the latter for home consumption. A chest of tea in China weighs from 100 to 110 pounds, a half-chest from 60 to 70,and there are smaller boxes or caddles, containing from five to ten pounds. The chests are filled to their utmost capacity, the packers even jumping in the boxes to get in the last possible ounce.The chests are made perfectly tight, and matted and interlace outside with bamboo netting, as we get them on this side of the water. The tea is then ready for exports, and is ordered by importers through a tea taster. The taster is paid from $2,000 to $8,000 per year, and his modus operandi is follows: He has a long, narrow table, on which 60 or 70 cups are set; a boy weighs exactly one ounce from a simple box into one of these cups, and if he has samples enough, all the cops are used. Hot water is then poured into each cup, and after 5 minutes the boy calls the master, who sips from every cop, holds the liquid in his mouth a moment, then ejects it and notes in his book the quality of the tea. The purchaser orders upon his taster’s estimate, and when his package arrive at the warehouse, about one in 20 is opened for comparison with the sample. If it proves off inferior grade, a material reduction is at once made in the price, so that without the connivance with the tea-taster the adulteration of tea next to impossible in China. Sometimes after the first drawing the leaves are collected and redressed, but this is the only way in which adulteration is practiced. In comparing the contents of the chest with the sample, the leaves are examined to see whether they are old or young or middle-aged. The younger the leaves choicer will be the tea. Tea in China means black tea, unless green is specially designated. It is still in dispute, even it its home, whether black and green tea belong to the same species. They are branches of the same variety, black or green according to the localities where they grow. If a seed of black tea be planted in the green tea region, a few generation will make them both alike. When black tea is high, green can readily be turned into black, but black cannot be made to appear green. The latter obtain its bluish color artificially, Prussian blue being used in the coloring, but in such small quantities as to be harmless. The annual average yield of a tea plant is about 20 ounces, and too much rain affects the quality as well as the amount. The plants live from 20 to 80 years, and, when old, are frequently cut down and a young shrub grafted into the old stock. Quicker returns are thus obtained, but the plant does not last so long. Ten or twelve drawings of pure tea are required to obtain a limpid liquid, and 15 drawings will not usually exhaust all its strength. Tea is drank pure in China, but there are very different ways of preparing it. The Chinese tea connoisseurs purchase an article costing variously from $16 per pound to $20 an ounce. If he uses this choicest kind, which is only grown on the tops of the mountain, and of which only 10 or 15 piculs are produced in the Kingdom, he has a “baby” tea-pot, an inch and a half high and about an inch in diameter. A pinch of tea is put in, about 20 drops of hot water turned on, and it is ready to sit. It would be very intoxicating to drink much; even the taste of a sip will remain in the throat for hours after the tea has evaporated. The more common way of tea drinking is to have a teapot six feet high and three feet in diameter, kept warm, ready for anyone to drink who chooses. With good tea it is not very important how it is prepared, but the best way, perhaps, is to first warm the pot with hot water, then put in tea and pour boiling water upon it. The tea should never be boiled. The common people drink the tea stalks. The seeds are about the size of a small cherry, and from those not wanted for planting oil is expressed and used for cooking pomatum purposes. Much of the black tea comes from Bohea or “Woo-e” District, which produces the Pecco, or white haired tea, Orange Pecco (highest fragrance), Red Plum blossoms and Dragon’s whiskers. Hung Foo or common tea is made valuable by labor. Our English breakfast is of this kind, and it sells for from $25 to $60 per picul. Green tea is classed under the names of Gunpowder, Imperial, Hyson and other names well known here. Oolong is recognized by a Chinese as Black Dragon tea, and rank high, being a black tea with green tea flavor. The tea plant is not extremely old in China. It is discovery only dates back about 1400 years. The trade was confined to the immediate neighborhood of the kingdom until comparatively a recent date. In 1669 the shipments to England were 147 3-4 pounds, but in 1859 they had increased to 85,000,000 pounds, and in 1870 the British government derived a revenue of over £6,000,000 from the tax on tea. Indirectly the United States owes its independence to tea. Chemists, botanists, and doctors may disagree upon its merits, but it has always been a favorite beverage with brainworkers; it cheers and invigorates, but does not inebriate. The Chinese are proverbially healthy and the tea-taster is long-lived.</text>
    <text Source="Springfield Daily Republican" Date="1873-05-19" Title="The North Church Sunday School" Page="8">﻿My young friends, this is a school on Sunday;  you learned here nothing about grammar, but everything about Christ. Many schools study philosophy and astronomy, but those branches of study are nothing, compared with what is taught here. The learning of the schools makes men proud of their philosophy, but in Sunday school we become like little children before One higher than the greatest philosopher. What these children are taught here, raises them higher than even the rulers of many great, almost civilized nation. I would like a Sunday school class of kings: the shah of Persia, the sultan of Turkey, the emperors of China and Japan, and many more; and if I should say to these wise men, capable of commanding vast armies and governing millions and millions of people, “Who made the world?” – they would tell me “Chance.” These great rubberheads know nothing of the religion of Jesus Christ or of the felicity of heaven. They are groping in the dark, as you have to feel your way when you go down cellar in the evening without a light. I have conversed with many great man, viceroys and governors in all parts of the world, and with all sorts of men everywhere, but in no other country have I seen such a diffusion of intelligence as in the United States. I do not say this to flatter you, but it is true, and I attribute much of it to the influence of Sunday Schools. They comprise a great many of population, reaching from ocean to ocean and from the gulf of Mexico to the St. Lawrence River. You have read in your Bibes how at Athens Paul found an altar to “the unknown God.” The Greeks were then remarkable for their education, but they saw no God, in the clouds or in the sea; and these children are wiser than they. It is Sunday school teaching that has done the work. This is your 26th anniversary, and I bid you a happy new year. In a quarter of a century you have sent many to bless society and will send many more, but you much not be discouraged if little is accomplished. We are all mere materials: some gold, some wood, and some straw; ot makes little difference which, but if you are only straw, with activity and perseverance your straw will become a hundred times its first value. I want you to remember how on your 26th Sunday school anniversary a man from China told you about that class of kings, and when you think of it, remember, too, the story of God’s once being very angry with the people of Sodom. He meant to burn up the city, but Abraham asked him to spare it for the sake of 50 good men, and then, feeling very unease, he asked it for 30, and at least even for the sake of 10 good men. Each time God said “yes,” unil Abraham stopped asking. God will accept even very little from us, and I have no doubt if Abraham had kept on asking, God could have spared the city for the sake of two or three righteous men. God gives us a great deal, and yet he is glad to have us give him very little. If you only keep one of the ten commandments and break all the rest, you will be rewarded for that. There is a mighty nation in the East that has endured 4000 years, and sands to-day, amid the wreck of surrounding nations. That nation kept one of the commandments, the fifth. They honor their parents, and verily their days have been long in the land. In China, if the children are playing their their parents enter the room, the children keep very still until they are allowed to play again; or if a guest comes in and the father rises to hand him a chair, all the children run to take the chair from their father and give it to the guest. If a child murders its parent, he or she must be chopped into 10,000 pieces – into mince pie meat – but if a father kills his child, the law does not touch him, because it deems such a crime unnatural and not to be thought of except under the most tremendous provocation. Families make up the nation, and their behavior denotes a well or ill-regulated country. Here the Sunday school should be the fountain-head of good government in the nation and at home, everywhere teaching you to live so as to be happy here and hereafters.</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-10-16" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">The warm and hearty welcome to Clinton, with which you have extended to me, calls for thanks &amp; acknowledgement on my part. Your much esteemed favor dated the 7th inst. greeted my eyes on my return from a tour of inspection of the boys placed under my charge in this country. The Chinese government has determined to send 120 pupils to be educated in this country in the arts and sciences. These boys are to be sent in four installments of 30 each year. They are selected from a preparatory school established by the government in Shanghai. The limit of their stay in the United States, in order to obtain their profession, is fifteen years. But if they can do it sooner, so much the better. From all the accounts of teachers under whom these boys have been placed, the unanimous opinion, is, that they are bright and clever youths, obedient and very studious. For the first two or three years they will simply learn the rudiments of the English language. I have two sons attending the school in this place. They will enter the high school by next quarter. I am greatly indebted to you for the catalogue of Hamilton College sent to me by you both here &amp; China &amp; also news papers. I am too busy at present to leave my post, but I have made up my mind to visit Clinton next Commencement with my whole family of 3 sons and 3 daughters and Mrs Laisun. I may attend the Junior Exhibition, but I can not promise I see by the catalogue that yourself and Professor Charles Avery are the only gentlemen I know. I long to see you &amp; talk of old time, but that pleasure must be reserved for the future. My family joins me in very kind regards to you and all yours.</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-10-28" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">Yours dated the 21st inst: with two catalogues, one the Rural School &amp; the other the Triennial have been duly received. &amp; for which place accept my thanks. At present I have no boys to send to the school you recommend so highly. My two sons I am anxious to have them by my side. Of the second instalment of boys, we may think proper to send a couple to Clinton. They will be here sometime next summer. My other colleagues seem to be averse to send boys away from any of the New England States. However I can not do any thing this time as we have no boys to send. After my tour I have been on my back with the dysentery, but I feel much better today. If I keep on improving, I may start for Clinton either on Friday or Saturday the 1st or 2nd proximo [=next month] in which case I will telegraph. As I am so uncertain in my movements, you must not build much hope on my promise. Will you please tell me where your brother Josiah is, and all about him, or I had better hear of him when I see you at the end of this week. My two sons are getting along very well in their studies &amp; will most likely be ready to enter college in less than three years preparation. We have had very dismal weather for three or four days past, in consequence of which I have not ventured to drive out on account of my health. The other members of my family seem to thrive in this new country. Hoping soon to have the pleasure of seeing your face,</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-10-31" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">I was just going to write to you when yours of yesterdays’ date came to hand. I was going to tell you that I must postpone my visit till after election day. If nothing prevents, I trust I shall be with you on the 8th of November. My family joins me in very kind regards to you + all yours.
</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-11-11" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">I am in receipt of a circular inviting my presence The Tifft House, in the city of Buffalo on the 14th of November on business of great importance to the Institution. I would heartily respond to this invitation had I not such a large family to look after + care for. Probably you may be shocked, if I were to tell you that I have 33 sons and 3 daughters in this country. For fear they may get into trouble, I am obliged to keep a constant watch over them. And besides there are so many much more able sons of Hamilton College to transact business than one who is just arrived from China I trust you will have me excused with the greatest esteem </text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-11-14" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">We are under great obligation to you for the pleasure we have enjoyed ourselves during our stay with you; the only regret we feel that we could not stay a little longer. Since I came back I have been revolving something in my mind by which I think I can do something for Hamilton College, if you think it can be done. I am not acquainted with the financial state of the college, but from what little I have heard it is not very flourishing. You told me to write out my lectures and appear before the public. Now it strikes me, if I could prepare these lectures to please the public I will devote the proceeds to the establishing of a Scientific department in the institution. There must be a tact in the Manoevre of this enterprise, the details of which I will give if it is favorably looked upon by you &amp; others of the Falculty [sic] when I will run to Utica &amp; confer with you. I herewith inclose the photos of the members of my family. I trust you had a very good &amp; interesting meeting with thte Alumni in Buffalo. Willie is constantly talking of College Hill &amp; you. It is a great epoch in his life. We got home all safe &amp; found the rest of my children very well. With unremitting Kind regards both to misses North &amp; yourself</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-11-25" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">I am under very great obligation to you for the “Clinton Courier” and Catalogue of Hamilton College for the year 1872. I do not know to whom I am indebted for the encomium with which some one has touched me up in its columns. He has given me more than I really deserve. I am working hard to get up a series of lectures on China. It will depend very much upon what you and others with you say; whether the public shall pay for what they hear from me, or receive them gratis. If my proposition is adopted, I think I can devise means to increase the amount thus gleaned to a considerable sum. Let us devise a plan by which we shall be able to extend the means of education, + make the institution independent forever. I have a great deal of time in my hand by which I can help towards this great cause. This idea never came to my head until you told me to prepare written lectures for the benefit of the public. When on my way to Springfield I have been thinking why not get these lectures up for the benefit of Hamilton College as well. If I could have known this before hand, I certainly would have joined you to the Buffalo meeting. And with the support of the Alumni throughout the country such a thing must be successful. The very novelty of a Chinaman going about the country lecturing would attract many; to say nothing of the worthy object for which these lectures are given. I am engaged in writing the “Four Professions” namely: The Literary, the Agricultural, the Laborial, (if there be any such word) and the Mercantile. The next subject will be the physical geography of the Celestial Region; then the Opium question, or the Chinese civilization; then Emigration or some others. If you have any works of recent publication on any of the above subject, especially on the physical geography of the Chinese empire, you will greatly oblige by letting me have the loan of them for a short time. Let me hear from you soon. I hope you have received the photos sent to you some days ago. My colleagues have made up their minds to visit New York some time before the 10th proximo: whether they will go as far as Washington I can not say. Please to make our kindest regards to the Misses North and Ned. The same to yourself. P.S. I received also the pamphlet containing the addresses relating to Mrs. North + her father Item[?]: S. Newton Dexter. Please accept my thanks for it.</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1872-12-02" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">I have read yours of the 25th and 26th ulto: I am glad that I find much sympathy from you in the object I wish to accomplish. If Dr Hudson will write to me requesting my assistance to get a new library for the Stone Church Sabbath School, I will give a trial to my ability, whether I can hope for greater enterprise. At present it is useless to count the chickens before they are hatched. When we get the funds we shall be able then to tell to what purpose it shall be appropriated. I do not know as yet I shall be able to go to Washington before New Year. I may possibly go to New York. I have nearly finished my discourse on the division of professions. It is hard to get my mind together to write a lecture as I am entirely unaccustomed to anything of the kind. If I succeed in doing any good it would be mainly owing to the good cause, rather than to any “spicy sentences” that I may try to rake up. I note your words, “To lecture well is an art to be studied.” Yes, study I will, I am determined to give what I have of China for the benefit of Hamilton College. Through painful &amp; constant study. Dr Hudson has not written to me yet. Perhaps we had better wait till the college vacation is over &amp; then lecture, which will suit me the better because it will give me more time to practice on the art. But suit your convenience I shall be ready in a few days. Please make our kind remembrance to all your family</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-01-07" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">You have no doubt returned to your post by this time. I was indeed very sorry for not being able to go with you to the capital at the time you did. Mr. Yung Wing and myself had a certain work to accomplish. I could not very well leave then. The Committee on Foreign Affairs in Washington has sent us an invitation to go down and lay before them a certain plan by which the cause of Education for the Chinese may be enlarged. I intend to start the middle of this week and shall be absent for one week or ten days. Enclosed I have written a letter to Dr. Hudson, which please forward. It is a change of time for my appearance in Clinton. The 5th of February is agreed upon. I shall be away from home for one week. I would ask your advice whether it would be proper to offer myself to the people in Utica and Albany, to each one evening, a lecture on some subject connected with China, if they would provide me a respectable place and a fair good audience. I give them gratis. I can lecture on the 5th in Clinton, 6th in Utica, 7th in Albany and be at home on the evening of the 8th. If you think the thing advisable will you then, please get the Utica + Albany people to give me a place to lecture. I have several reasons for doing this 1st To get a practice in public speaking 2nd To get the American people more acquainted with China 3rd To prepare myself for the great work of establishing scholarships or something greater in Hamilton College. 4th To raise a crusade against the British government for the sales of opium and encouraging that trade to the destruction of so many human lives. This use of opium in the East is so prevalent and the effect so destructive, that it is high time for some one to rouse the public sympathy to remove this overflowing poison. All the members of my family are well, except Willie, who has an attack of scarletina. I trust he will get over it soon. Give our united kind regard to the Misses North and Ned. My daughter anticipates great pleasure in meeting with them.</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-01-18" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">Yours dated the 13th inst: is to hand. I have decided to give before the Stone Church Audience a lecture on the “Manners &amp; customs of the Chinese” as I first proposed. I have also written to Dr Hudson to that effect. If I have the chance of speaking in Albany I will there give them a slight dose of the opium. In Utica I will speak of Chinese Education. By the way, if I lecture on opium I should like very much to have the notice given in the papers of the place in which I am to lecture, several days before hand. So that I may have newspaper reporters note what I say in their papers. On account of Willie’s illness I did not dare to leave home for Washington; but now he is much better, I trust I shall be able to leave sometime next week. Mrs Laisun has been attacked with a very severe cold &amp; was confined in bed for one whole week. She is now better, and able to come to the table. I am extremely obliged to you for your forethought in making provisions for our visit. My daughter will stay with the Misses North and I will put up in the village. We all look forward with great deal of pleasure when we bring you our respects in February. I gave to the Springfield people at their urgent request, a dilution of “tea” the strong taste of which gives a “flagrant flavor to their tongue.” as you will see by the paper I herewith send you. With love from us all to you all</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-02-03" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">I am very sorry you have given yourself so much trouble in writing five times to Albany I suppose, + then receive no answer. I shall go to Watertown after I finished Clinton + Utica. I have promised Rev. Mr Keyes to pay him a visit + speak to the church where he attends next Sunday. So it is just as well I do not lecture in Albany. You will find me + my daughters at Mr. Bradford S. Merrell’s any time on Tuesday if you chose to call for us. I should prefer going to Clinton in the 3:30 p.m. train. I send you herewith one box of tea per the “Merchants’ Express” freight already paid. We are all improving. Love from us all to you all. Till we meet I bid you good by</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-04-04" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">Professor Edward North Revered + dear Sir, It is quite an age since I wrote to you or heard from you. I have nothing of importance to note, save our visit to Washington. I have been called upon to speak on Chinese subjects in a dozen places since I left you. My evenings would all be occupied if I would consent to have them so. The New England people are great on hearing lectures on other countries. The calls have been so numerous that I am obliged to levy a tax of $30 with all expenses paid, which was readily agreed upon. Mr Northrop the Secretary of Education of Connecticut alone pays me a good sum for attending the Teachers Institute which he holds from place to place at the expense of the State. Mrs Laisun Miss Lena my second daughter, Willie + myself started for Washington on the 28th February. We stopped over night at Bloomfield N.J. where I met Rev. Mr G. J Knox brother to J. J Knox in the Treasury. Of course we acknowledged our common Alma Mater, + felt refreshed and invigorating to talk of old times in college. His wife was a daughter of Mr. Faik the merchant of Clinton. Poor lady she was sighing awfully for the hills of Clinton + its literary advantages. She said as soon as Summer comes she is off for home. We reached Washington on the 1st March + took rooms in the Wormley’s where we had already engaged them one week beforehand. The cars were literally jammed full. For some distance I was obliged to stand up. From all parts of the country cars were pouring in like smoke. We remained about one week. Before the inauguration, we improved our time in visiting the places of interest, such as the Capitol Patent office, Treasury, Smithsonian Institute and many others. On the 4th I took my family up to the Capitol + witnessed every thing that went on. The weather was bitterly cold. Afterward we went to Dr. Peter Parker’s corner of the Presidents Square + had a fine view of the soldiers as column after column passed on before that president’s stand. We made the acquaintance of the members of the Cabinet, the Secretary of State + his lady, Mr. Eaton Bureau of Education the president + vice president. When we were at the White House we were introduced to the president + saw all the big lions of the Union down to the beggars that swarm the place for an office somewhere. Willie + Lena were the hero + heroine of the time. He was the prince + she was the princess. After two weeks dissipation I came home pretty well used up. I also went back to Bloomfield N.J. + spent another week. I shall stay at home now + rest awhile. June is fast approaching. My children are looking forward with great anticipation of good time in Clinton. We are all well. Please remember us to all the members of your dear family. I tried to hunt Dexter out in W. but failed. Willie sends love to ‘Fessor North. P.S. Annie is anxiously waiting for Miss Laura’s letter.</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-07-12" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">Yours date the 28th and 30th ulto respectively came safely to hand. They would have been answered long ago had I not other obligations to discharge. As I returned home, an urgent request was sent to me to prepare a paper for the “American Teacher’s Institute” which was held in Concord N.H. where I had been for the past week. I came home late last evening and now I take the first opportunity to thank you for the affectionate regards you expressed in your letter of the 28th of last month. I was very sorry indeed not to have seen more of you during commencement, but I knew well your time was occupied constantly in the duties of that occasion. I did not wonder at all of your severe illness after the excitement was over. We all enjoyed ourselves hugely. Mrs Laisun &amp; the young ladies were very much interested in all the exercises. If my life is spared as well as the lives of my sons till next year, I hope to take them to Clinton &amp; have them catch the inspiration of “Old Hamilton.” I let them go up to Amherst to attend the commencement there after their school. They made the acquaintance of one who had just attended the exercises of Hamilton College. He told them that the speaking &amp; the subjects of their speeches were very tame compared with those of Hamilton. And this young man had an idea of entering Amherst too. My sons also told me that they did not think the speeches very brilliant. I am happy to inform you that my sons after an examination of two days were admitted to the High school with flying colors. Between two &amp; three years more they will be ready for college. The principal of the High school was well pleased with their papers and commended them very highly. Our city is in great excitement about the college regatta. The local papers as well as the local people talk nothing else all day but the regatta. I am truly sorry Hamilton College is not represented - and for the absence of which my children are obliged to wear the color of Yale the nearest to Hamilton. The two Misses Branch who are spending their summer in Greenfield the sisters of Branch who had just graduated are expected to come on here and spend a day or two with us to the regatta. I wish you and the young ladies could come and attend this grand fete of sculls and shells; but I am afraid you are all already gone to some summer retreat and this invitation is too late for you to get ready to be here. You requested me to write down what I said at the commencement. I am afraid I shall not be able to do it, because I do not remember what I said. I know I did not say any thing wrong. So you will please excuse me. If the newspaper reporter had taken down my useless speech, he is welcome to publish it. At the commencement I suppose I received a degree, of what nature I am not able to tell. Whether hot or cold, high or low good or bad the diploma I got before in the presence of a clapping crowd is perfectly silent and blank. It contained however, a small slip of paper with these words. “It will be filled up &amp; sent to you as soon as convenient.” Will you please see the proper Mandarin and send me the Warrant as early as he can make it convenient. Whatever expenses occurrent on such warrant being issued shall be paid by the party on whom it is served as soon as the amount is named. My family enjoyed the exercises of the commencement very much &amp; it is quite an epoch in the history of their life. Our united love to all your family</text>
    <text Source="Hamilton College Archive" Date="1873-09-10" Title="Letter to Professor North" Page="1">Although I have not had a line from you for a long time, I have heard of your whereabouts. Now it seems to me that you have slighted us without good reason. I was told that you and your young ladies were spending your summer in Nantucket at the seaside. Unless you have taken the seven sides of an octagon to reach that place, you must necessarily pass our city. My family complains most woefully that you should be in our midst and not come to see us, say nothing of giving us the pleasure and honor of entertaining you in our home, + show you something of our city. We have kept ourselves very quiet at home. We made no trip to the Springs, Mountains, or Seashores. Since seeing you at the commencement our number of students has been augmented by another installment of thirty lads. The poor little fellows had a rough reception at their debut into this country. At De Moines the train in which they were traveling was attacked by banditti. Although they lost nothing by them, they were more frightened than hurt. Two days after their arrival in this place, they all were placed in their new homes. My colleague Mr. Yung Wing has left for China to be absent for six months. I have now double work to do, which takes up so much of my time that I have refused the many calls for my lecture. Willie has just begun to learn his lessons. He gets along remarkably well. Amy is attending a day school near us. She stands head in the school, although when she first entered, her teacher thought she being a foreign girl, must be very deficient in her education. My two sons are in the high school and are doing very well. I feel I am one of the happiest of men to see my children having such inestimable opportunity of improving their minds. I am certain I shall have nothing to leave them, but the legacy of good education, with that they must shift for themselves in the world. President Brown’s son and daughter called on us a week or ten days ago on their way to Dartmouth. Miss Brown partially promised to stop with us over night on her way back to Clinton. Our love to you all.</text>
    <text Source="The Friend of China: The Organ Of The Society For The Suppression Of The Opium Trade" Date="1875" Title="Meeting at Devonshire House" Page="8 - 27">As my friend Mr. Hanbury has told you I am here in England on an educational mission. I had no idea when I came to this country that a society for the suppression of the Opium Trade had an existence in this great city. When I was informed of the fact, I was very glad to find that such a society had originated among a people who had to a great extent forced the trade upon the Chinese nation. It reveals an anomalous and paradoxical state of things. You do and you do not; you force and yet you restrain. To bring such a state of facts before the Chinese mind would involve the making of a statement which would be characterized as entirely absurd. I take it as a matter of course that the Opium traffic is and must be a curse to any nation beyond a certain limit, such limit being drawn at the point where opium ceases to be necessary or useful for medicinal purposes. Druggists and chemists have ascertained that opium is one of the best remedies for the cure of certain diseases to which humanity is subject, but though the Chinese are very much diseased, I must say I do not think opium, as they use it, is likely to cure them. On the contrary, I think it must and does tend to ruin the Chinese as a nation. The effects of the drug upon the Chinese since its first introduction among them have been something very marvellous and wonderful to describe. There have been thousands, indeed I may say millions, of families ruined by its use. No arithmetic can properly or accurately compute the amount of evil which has worked. It is not necessary for me to dwell upon this point, because I know that every person in this audience will agree with me that the whole result of the traffic in its effects upon the people simply ruinous. All who have travelled in the East whether they have been engaged in manual occupations, or have been members of the learned professions, or have been occupied in missionary labour, will testify without exception to the fact that the effects of opium upon the Chinese have been simply ruinous – no words in fact can adequately describe the evil effects of opium upon the human system as exemplified in the case of the Chinese. I may remark in passing that in China opium is not eaten as in England, America, and all over Europe, but is smoked. There is however, no difference in the effect it has upon the human system between the consumption of opium by smoking and eating. If we go back to the year 1770, we shall find that not more than a few chests of opium were imported by China; at the time of the first English war with China, not much more than thirty years ago, only a few thousand chests were imported annually – and part of this was used for medicinal purposes – but since then the annual import has grown to tens of thousands, and the increase is still going on. And there is no possibility of breaking the people of the habit as long as the import continues. When once a man has contracted an inveterate habit of opium-smoking, he cannot stop it without endangering his life – it becomes a case of life or death with him. It is a fortunate circumstance in the economy of nature that human beings will cling to life, but it is a fact, as far as the Chinese are concerned, that they cling to life, but yet go on taking poison every day of their lives. I will not dwell at length upon the use of opium, but I will not leave this branch of the subject without mentioning some of the horrible results which flow from it. My friend Dr. Lockhart, whom I have known for more than twenty years, would be able to give you, perhaps, more information on this point than I can. One of the most common results of the use of the drug is, that the opium-smoker cannot be trusted. He entirely loses all his principles of integrity – if he ever had any – he loses every energy which the Deity has bestowed upon him, and this in order to satiate his appetite. To the same end he will sell his children and pawn his wife. could bring not one or two, or hundred, or thousand, but tens of thousands of cases forward in support of this statement. This being the state of things and the evil still going on, this society has been formed, as suppose, for the purpose of influencing men of standing and also the Government in order to the final suppression of this diabolical traffic. It is all very well for one party to make an effort, but unless there  is a combined effort put forth by all who are interested in the matter, the Chinese will continue to use the drug in spite of all the moral influences which may be brought to bear upon them. From my small experience of Chinese officials, I can say that there exists among them a strong desire to put an end to the traffic and its consequent evils. I know that this wish animates officials so high in the service of their country as Tseng Kwo-fan, Li Hung Cheung, and Shin Paou Ching, the last-named of whom is head of the Chinese Arsenal, and was selected by the Chinese Government to proceed to Formosa and settle the difficulty which arose between his own country and Japan. With regard to Shin Paou Ching I may say that although it is entirely inconsistent with the rules and customs of the Chinese Empire to 4 man to perform important official business in his own province, he has been chosen by the Government as Imperial Commissioner, and sole Generalissimo of the 10,000 troops who were sent to Formosa under the circumstances have just mentioned. This will show the confidence which is reposed in Shin Paou Ching, and the high position which he holds in his native country. He is a man of great influence, disinterestedness, and liberality; a man who while not what in this country would be called Conservative, is not likely to grasp at every new innovation. I have had many conversations with the officials whose names I have mentioned, and each of them has expressed a desire that some effectual means should be taken to put an end to the traffic. It has been suggested that the import duty should be raised, but if that was done the English Government would say, “Look at your treaty.” If on the other hand the Chinese Government were to dispute the introduction of opium to their country from India on the ground that they did not desire it, the English Government would again say, “Look at your treaty.” Thus it is that with every wish to put an end to the opium traffic in the interest of the people, the hands of the Chinese Government are tied by the treaty. At the time when China opened her ports, and opium was smuggled into the country, the English said nothing about the treaty, while China could say nothing, because she had no power of resistance. The main difficulty lies in the fact that British merchants go out to China and the East to make fortunes, and make fortunes they will, must, and shall, with the assistance of the British Government, whether China lives or dies. The course of events in this connexion reminds me of the story of the father who, when his son was about to leave England for the East in order to seek his fortune, said to the boy, “ John, make money; make it honestly you can, but ––,” and then he stopped: the “but” spoke quite a volume of meaning. These are the facts with regard to the opium traffic in China, and the question remains: “What are we to do?” My answer to this is that I do not know. The Government is against us, and the merchants are carrying on their trade under, and according to, the treaty. We can do nothing, and, as I have said, the high officials in China, who are as anxious as we are to put a stop to the traffic, are equally powerless with ourselves. This has been the state of things up to the present time, but I shall think my mission has been accomplished if I can return to China and inform my friend Shin Paou Ching, that a body of English philanthropists in the City of London have formed themselves into an Anti-opium-traffic association, and that they will do the utmost that lies in their power to influence their own Government and important official people abroad in order to put an end to the trade. It will afford me great satisfaction to inform my friend that this society of which I speak, and whose members I am now addressing, is not composed of the “riff-raff” of London, or of men who have no brains, but consists of men of high standing, learning, and well-balanced minds, who look to the interests of humanity for their own sake, and not in order merely to accumulate wealth by promoting a diabolical trade like that in opium. It will afford me the utmost satisfaction to assure my friend that there is a body of men in London quite ready to extend the right hand of fellowship to any body of men in China who desire to put an end to the trade which is ruining their country by utterly demoralizing and debasing the vast majority of its inhabitants. Passing on to another branch of the subject I would venture to express the opinion that in sheer self-defence the Chinese are at the present moment cultivating the poppy in all parts of the empire. The principle upon which they act is this: they say we must do something to put an end to the importation of opium, and the best thing we can do is so far to cultivate the poppy and produce opium in our own country, as that no profit can be gained by its export from other countries for sale in the Chinese markets. This the Chinese say not because they delight in the use of the drug, but merely as a matter of self-defence. It may be said that this is a very absurd way of putting an end to the consumption of opium in China, but it is the only course which can be adopted by the Chinese themselves. In former years the cultivation of the poppy in China was an offence punishable, and punished, by imprisonment, confiscation, and even death. The law still remains, but the Government wink at its infringement, and, though passed in comparatively recent times, the law is practically obsolete. As I have said the Chinese cultivate the poppy in self-defence, and when the two parties in England and China so far agree as to put an end to the importation of opium from India, the growth of the poppy will cease in the whole Chinese empire, except in so far as it is necessary to produce opium for medicinal purposes, and that will probably be prescribed by law. I am afraid that tho bulk of the Chinese people do not understand this question as far as its details are concerned, but I believe that all the Chinese population are agreed in believing that tho opium traffic is a curse. The sentiment of filial piety in China is very strong, and a son when asked by his father for money to be expended in a perfectly harmless and necessary way, will not think of refusing although he knows that will be devoted to the purchase of opium for smoking. This must and does produce in the son’s mind a feeling of distrust which cannot be eradicated, and which must tend to destroy the feeling of trust and confidence which ought to exist between members of the same family. Again, the opium-smoker turns day into night. He sleeps all day and works all night – not at any legitimate business but at the pipe. He dreams away his life. In order to gratify his passion for the opium which is destroying him he will pawn his house and all it contains, and as I said in the early part of my speech, he will sell his children and pawn his very wife. No language can describe all the horrors which result from the use of opium in China; it involves a state of existence which the Chinese describe as “living in second hell.”
The very fact of carrying out the scheme I have described must result in the creation of a mutual feeling of friendship, and a good understanding between the peoples of the two countries which can only result in advantage to both. There is no doubt that the English language is becoming every day more commonly spoken in China and the East generally in official circles, and I therefore think it most important that knowledge of the kind I have described should be widely diffused among the class of persons who are to be the Chinese officials of the future. For this reason I glory in my own knowledge of the English language, and hope that the Chinese boys who may hereafter be sent to England may learn to speak your language a great deal better than can the speaker who has been addressing you, and who, in closing his remarks, thanks you for a patient and courteous hearing.
In China there are three classes of smokers: the inveterate smokers, the moderate smokers, and the indifferent smokers. The census would be difficult to obtain, but I should say that the majority of the inveterate smokers would be found among the lower classes, who use refuse opium, which has the effect of increasing the craving for the drug.
The primary effect upon the consumer of opium is on the body.
Such cases are very few. The effect of opium upon the body is that the face gets very sallow and emaciated, and the physique generally becomes reduced and slender. The eyes assume an appearance of blankness, the retina seeming altogether to have lost its lustre. The effect upon the mind is – that the opium-smoker loses his mind altogether.
My observation has shown me that in China there are many persons who never take the pipe at all except on occasions when they are paying visits of courtesy to friends who are in the habit of using the drug. This occasional use of opium has no evil effect at all. Further, there are two ways of smoking, the one being to inhale the smoke into the lungs, and then exhale it either through the mouth or nostrils; the other simply to take the smoke into the mouth, and puff it out again immediately. The first method is that of the habitual or inveterate smoker, the second that of the smoker who simply indulges occasionally as a matter of etiquette or courtesy. Unless a smoker of the last class takes two, three, or four pipes, and then resumes on the following day, it will have no evil effect. If, however, he does resume, the chances are that he will keep on, and in ten or fifteen days he will become addicted to it and develop into an inveterate smoker.
The statement of Dr. Ellis is undoubtedly accurate, but I would remind him that the effect of opium when eaten is much greater and much more injurious than when it is smoked, and this last is the invariable way of consuming the drug in China.
</text>
  </chan_laisun>
  <yung_wing>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1853-06-26" Title="Poetry" Page="1">There is a morning and a day when first snow fall.
The good remembers the evergreen; the wicked remembers the flower
We only see the evergreen but not the flower.
At present, the one is inferior to the other.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1848-06-07" Title="Letter to Gallandt" Page="1">I am sorry that I have disappointed you of the rod which I promised in the cars on my way down to New York. It was my intention to spend only a week in both places. New York and Philadelphia, and afterwards go to Hartford on my way home and spend a few days in your family but Mr. Brown’s friend in those places urged me to stay, and to make a longer and till my which vacation was really passed, left me only one day to return home in warm before the commencement of another term, and now I take the opportunity to write you a few lines, asking you to excuse me of breaking the promise. I ought to have written to you before this time if it had not been my negligence, which lays the base of bad habit. Ever since I left you last winter, it has been my sincere desire to see you and I was perfectly overwhelmed with my to write you and Eddy unexpectedly in the cars, and I do feel bad afterwards when I disappointed you after all your trouble in coming out to see me. I shall try to find time to go down to Hartford and see you before I leave the country for anywhere. I wish you and your family well, give my respects to them all, with my hearty thanks to Mary Gallandt for the fine apple which she lent me by the Brown. Please to let me know whether you have any choice eggs and chickens with you, if not I try get you some. Please to correct my mistakes if you can upon time to give me an answer. However I have opportunity I will write a longer letter. Believe me to be one of 
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1872-02-17" Title="Letter to Professor Noah Porter" Page="1">I take great pleasure to inform you that on the 1st of October 1871, the Chinese government which bring
From standard, before any could be admitted. The young students are taught both English and Chinese in the preparatory school for which purpose, the day is equally divided between each study. The whole establishment is conducted by Chinese of whom there is a superintendent there teacher of Chinese, there of English.
The examination of candidates is conducted all the year round through only the printed number of thirty is selected to the school abroad. The plan of primate only contemplates sending thirty students every year for four consecutive years, thus making the total number of the one hundred and twenty.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1876-10-04" Title="Letter to Franklin B. Dexter" Page="1">The honor confirmed on me by the Corporation of Yale College as outlined by the Diploma recovered yesterday is too great and distinguished to be appropriated by me individually. Without ever forgetting its corresponding demands and obligations on me as a son of Yale
I shall bear it only for eluin and the Chinese and regard it as a national decoration made by the youngest but most progressive nation to the older but most essertive people in the world, as an encouragement to the …
With humble thanks to the corporation,
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-10-08" Title="Letter to Franklin B. Dexter" Page="1">To the best of my knowledge, I believe my relations to the College church has never been disturbed or severed. In this respect, I think the record is correct.
On account of my frequent change of domicile, I prefer if the church does not object where my connection with it continued till I am......Permanently located.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-02-26" Title="Letter to Addison Van Name" Page="1">I shall be very happy and ready at any time to send my Chinese book to the College provided the endowment in the Chinese Professorship becomes a settled fact.
I hope Yale will not delay the matter long till Harvard authenticate her.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-03-01" Title="Letter to Addison Van Name" Page="1">Enclosed herewith, please find a list of forty different works containing 1237 volumes. They will be sent to your care in four cases as soons as I receive a notice from you that the chair for a Chinese Professorship is established.
I have retained a few works for reference
The towly four dynasty histories belong to the mission.
If I send a copy I would gladly give it to the college.
To Williams will be able to give you an idea of the character of the books in the list.
I wish you speedy success in the sudowmuch.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1878-05-29" Title="Letter to Addison Van Name" Page="1">I send you by the N. York, N. Harow and Hartford R. R. fun cases of Chinese books through Bill Bros, Hartford to this against the muses sinually tes of your city who will deliver them to you in good order and conditions. This are prepaid as in R.R. receipts. The sinually will also deliver you four keys belonging to the cases.
A row list of the books is enveloped herewith. I hope they will reach you safely and become the nucleus of a respectable Chinese library.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1887-12-02" Title="Letter to Timothy Dwight" Page="1">I wish my membership in the Yale Congregational Church to be transferred to the asylum Hall Congregational Church, Hartford, Conn., if the record shows that my membership of the mufew congregational church had been duly made. A letter from you of the transfer will oblige.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1889-01-01" Title="Letter to Gallandt" Page="1">Monsoon Bartlet wish me to thank you for the kind involution for last Fridays little park gathering which they regret they could not attend; they join me in hearty wishes for a happy new year for you and your family.
I must take this opportunity to thank J. Gallandt for the memoirs of his father which I read with deep interest.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1909-12-13" Title="Letter to J.C." Page="1">The book, “My life in China and America”, will be delivered to you within today or tomorrow by admonish express for Yale University Library as a slight token of my love of Yale. 
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1910-01-13" Title="Letter to Mill Whedon" Page="1">Your favor of the 10th with was quite a surprise. I was very glad to … having seventy five students under training. It is a most interesting work though it involves a great deal of care, patience, and nerve on my work.
I am quite pleased that
You like my book. It is simple and narrative of a checked life. It is doubtful whather I would live in our again. But such as it is, I have given it to the world for what it is worth.
Its mitective spoke and objective are plain. I have tried my … best to live for China and her highest welfare.
I thank you for your kind words about the book. They are such that I shall always appreciate and keep fresh in my memory.
Hoping to see you soon and wishing you a happy new year
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1849-04-01" Title="Letter to Monson Malt" Page="1">As ashing is going back to China this month, it gives me a good opportunity to write to you. Been long I am going to stay here is a question not yet handled but you will probably hear from me with regards to that point in my next letter which I anticipate to write. I am glad that you and your family have wesped the destructive hurricane which we heard about not long ago and have safely arrived in China. I am sorry that I had not written to my friends in China, they however are still remembered and as soon as I find time, I will write to them. There is one particular and important subject which I wish to communicate to you in this letter, and if you are so kind as to carry out what a great desire you will do in a favour which has an intricate relation to my future sphere of life. The one and particular subject is this, that in earnestly wish that you will give employment to my brother Wing Chun and if I do work with too much I have one more request to make, which is this, that I wish you would talk to my uncle Yung Wing Cheong about my staying in this country several years longer. The reason why I make this request of you is … obvious, for I have a great … to get a … education, and there is great probability so much so that it amounts to … that I am going to stay, and of course you are aware that my feelings would not allow me to love my mother and the brother … I promised them all when I left China to return in two years or three years
And you know full well the pafinder of the Chinese, how they mispresent through, how and that they are not able to see as you or any only thread round do, the object, the advantage, and value of being educated. Ignorance and superstition have sealed up the noble facilities of these round, how can they appreciate through of dial worth. Consequently if I should stay, I beg you to talk to my uncle with all you might to present and enable them of the object of my stay in this country for 6 years more, and the sisthe which are from eduction in that till or good a strong as you ear his knowledge… help …, and what may be not ofen life of I live. Few of you talk to him, he has the opportunity and found a Chinese to speak to any mother and of my … brother is employed also, then in but my little … which should know stands in the way to prevent one to stay. At the same time there will be much f… my younger brother to go to school if I decide to stay. I want you to do it for me because you are better acquainted with the Chinese, at the same time they put some confidence in you than anybody else. Ashow is my cousin in whom my mother greatly confides in … working in your house … to him if you have time, how good a thing is to know and some had to know the services that all of which I am bearing. The painful thing which they do not … the … on these that they are of … that I will … the new … with … … …
Mr Brown had been teaching school during all the past month at Rome in New York State. Mrs Brown had been in Monson all the time. She is going to settle at Rome. I suppose you have heard by this time that old Zach was elected President of their … States. This many … … was my shout about half a column. We are all well. My kind regards to Mrs Williams and to all who enquire after me. Grace my many mistakes and bad writing. I hope to write to you again. Please write to me if you have time. What is the prospect in Chinese. Adieu.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1850-12-25" Title="Letter to W. M." Page="1">I am very sorry that I did not answer the two letters which I received from you sooner. My time for the fact you was pretty well employed in preparing myself for college. I suppose for the four … years. I shall have to … much later than before. I have succeeded in entering college this fall and have already … through the duties of our term and now enjoying the vacation of two weeks. This is the only time in which I expect to work to my … college life is something new to me, although I have a … of its rigid … in the academy. Things are conducted so regularly and the antics so receptive all the time that it … best calculated to make a practical man. My drive and focus through, (as they common say) that he has no time to think of anyone except study. There is also … and … among the students themselves. I … mental excitement than Yale is surrounded by with an atmosphere of ambition. I think a … ambition is production of good results but an inordinate degree is undoubtedly injurious. I more was … to such excitement. I enjoy its influence very much
College life would be much more pleasant to me. I think if I should … with a better preparation. All the amount of time I spent on the languages before I enter was a year and a half, and when I enquire how long others here spent on them, I was surprised to find that most of my classmates have at least three years of it while others six years. … … …, as well as the … ground and of contest. To enjoy college I think a person must have a firm fit or else endowed with indomitable energy and perseverance to drive his studies along.
I am very glad that my mother had … your and also that she is well. The last letter but one however brought me some mortifying news, in it she informs me of the death of my oldest brother and also of her own condition. That letter made me … for … … I gave up all prospects of coming to college although I was there filling lean you inform me whether the news was true or not, it would relieve me from great anxiety ever now, if you should let me know the whole matter. I sometimes feel as though I would give up what I have examined to go home with what education I have to render the condition of my mother and others who are known to me by the … of maternal affection
Better. I can see in my mind eye their condition. There is nothing that would … more than to think of them. Had it not been for some other reasons which however, I deem not superior to the duty which is due to a parent, I would have come home long ago. But as things now stand, I leave them all to you. Providence who will not allow a hair fall without his mother. The only thing that I can do for them now is to pray for them.
Afern has along lift me, he is now in Scotland. I feel very …, no one now lacks with me in china and I am fast loosing especially the … or … past of my china. I have therefore, and having no idea of remaining how long through college, when I left china, I did not bring with me any china books, recording. I have … a bill in the letter, the … which I stand in need of and will you be so kind as to purchased them for me. Any thing that I can do for you please let me know. I once drive great pleasure in driving it. I am very anxious to hear some of my classmates in china I have written to every one of them but received no answer. Aching has not written to me a word since he left here. I … from that … of the … is … and what there is in generally … this rather … ones capacity than about it. How do the Chinese and the foreigners getting along?
I had the fortune of seeing Mr. and Mrs. Brown in A. Haven since I entered college. They both were very well. I suppose you know that Mrs. Mary lives in the city. He is also studying theology. I must … my letter him. Give me best regards to Dr. Bridgiment and family, Dr. Bell, Dr. Happer and a host of others whom I always remember. 
N.B. Please send me one of Dr. Bells almanac for I have lost the … of the Chinese. Two if you please, one for 1851 and the other for ’52 if he has it.
I shall send you the money as soon as possible for those which as my knowledge of the Chinese language is my limited. I would like to have some of those books printed before you send them. Very much obliged to you for the many favors you do me.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1852-12-30" Title="Letter to Williams" Page="1">On acent of pressure of duty I was unable to answer your letter … … of Oct 1851. The things which you sent me by Mr. Bradly came safe into my hands. I am very much obliged to you for the trouble of purchasing and of sending them. The things all together cost somewhat near $4.50 four dollars and a half. In order to pay for them things and also to relieve my mother, I have sent $30.00 thirty dollars to Mr. Murwin of New York City who will send the money by … as soon as he can. Will you be in mind as to give the twenty five dollars to my mother … … … if she is not … … … … for I have not heard from her for a whole year. Will you do me the favor to … the … …
Between my sister and brother. I am … … my mother. The she to be offered until I returned. I would wonder that as the greatest helping that had cost believe … I know strong … that she want be loved. I only have an opportunity of looking to her. but and present I must … what … … I leave all the lives of my friends to the care of God who ruleth over every thing. I shall take my degree of B.A. and I have in the … of 1854. After that … to thinking of going home, and they my … … in relation to a … I have not as yet come to a definite conclusion on things in … … that I am going to stay agricultural aniversity. There are so many things. Many of them is and so … to a man who intends to benefit his country that I am strongly trying to know what to choose.
I shall not only rely upon my own judgement not … my … … … … regards is the choice. I hope and will direct … with his … I hope … …
Last summer, I had the pleasure of seeing and follow Bridgeman in New Haven. He had my … on … … … with the introduction of … into china. It has not appeared to me to him changed my in his personal appearance since I saw him at Conton. They had a my industry Chinese girl with them she … … a little … I want not … with her … … … different from … … I hope to … you soon. Remember me to all my friends. I should like to love the acquaintances of Mr. Lutin if I want be made by … Mr. Mrey and his mother are probably at … … now. Mr. Brown and family is at … New York …
Afun has left the … … and has entered into the profession of medicine and surgery with great enthusiasm. He is in Scotland. Please write me.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1853-07-27" Title="Letter to Williams" Page="1">I shall not take your time with a lengthy letter, but with a few lines only. My principal object in this short message is to … whether or not you have received the sum of $30.00 which I sent you sometime during the first part of last winter through Mr. Marvin. Besides the said money, I also sent you a letter by the over loud mail and directed it (if I recollect right) to the care of Mr. Arrow Shortride. In it I expressed to you my obligations if you should find it convenient to let my mother have $25.00 out of the thirty, and that if she should not be living the twenty-five dollars should be equally divided between my sister and brother. The remaining five dollars I meant for yourself for having purchased for me the Chinese books and which were sent to me by favor of Mr. Brooby. I should be glad to know whether my mother is living or not, and as you have the means of knowing it better than anybody else. You cannot do me a greater favor than to inform me of the fact and also the … of the money.
I have not heard from home for a long while and I rather suspect that the reason why my friends has not write to me is that they are unwilling to let me know anything about my mother, for fear … if they should tell me that she is not living. I would not probably return to china. Please write and let me know every thing that is important. I have just finished another years study. I have therefore only a year more to stay in college. I anticipate a glorious time with my senior studies for they agree with my … it is my intention to drive … them a … discipline of mind.
I hope to see you a year from this time if our lives are spared. I think I shall set out for china as soon as I graduate for I am anxious to return. I have been for long … please remember me to all those who are aquaint with me. Please write to me about the revolution for I am deeply interested in all its … How are the missionaries doing? And how is Dr. Brideman progressing in his … of the Bible. How is your own health? I hope you will excuse me for piling up such a heap of … upon you. I take the liberty to say however that in hurry how on the legitimate and … … of not hearing from you often show I desire I should be happy to have the acquaintance of the Chinese who was a member of Hamilton College. Will you please to give him my respect. I remain
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-02-19" Title="Letter to Doctor S. Walls Williams" Page="1">Your kind letter of the 17th instant was received this morning. I am happy to know of your safe return to this country again and I hope this letter will find you and your family in good health. I shall avail myself of the earliest opportunity to go down to New Haven to call on you.
The “Hartford Courant” of the 15th instant gave an account of our reception by the State Legislature on the 14th instant. I will send you a copy as soon as I could get one, but I doubt whether it could give you a fullest account than what you have seen in the New Haven papers.
Prince Kung … Tsung Li … undoubtedly would be pleased to see this account of our handsome treatment, and I am sure the cruel and … … treatment of the Chinese on the pacific slope by a curtain place of americans would at the same time rise up before them … … … contract, when they come to implore the actions of the respective legislatures.
Our Chinese students are making commendable progress in their studies. With the exception of the loss of one by death, they have all been in excellent health.
Our new building will soon be finished so that we expect to move into it by the 15th of March. We should be most happy to be honored with a visit from you at any time after the 14th april. With extreme
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-02-21" Title="Letter to Doctor Williams" Page="1">Last evening I sent you a copy of the Hartford Weekly Courant giving a full account of the reception. I am afraid you will not get it in time to … it in your letter to Mr. Sward. As I owe him a letter I will write and send him the notice but without any request to make it a subject of an official chapter.
I do not remember having seen your reply to the states (…) investigating committee, but should be glad to read it someday. I have accumulated quite a mass of facts and statements bearing in the (so called) … question in California. I am quite anxious to … … copies of the Congressional Investigating Committees
Return when it is printed.
I have … no stakes whatsoever in … any … and Washington. … would I be likely to do so till my associate arrives here. He may have his preferences and I should not like to act independently on the matter.
I herewith return Mr. Kings letter with thanks.
Aside from the emigration question which might be detaining Chin San Pin. I believe the Spanish Minister has preferred a china against china on account of a Spanish model wrecked on the … … some eight or nine years ago when her sailors were killed by the savages. Spain claim an … China should demand complete reparation for the … or from hundred thousands of Chinese men … by the Spaniards of Cuba, and for all those who have perished in the … much the … of taskmakers.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1877-06-07" Title="Letter to Dr. Williams" Page="1">I have two copies of the printed report of the Chinese Exhibit of the late Centennial Exhibitions but they are packed with my other books so that I do not know where to lay my hands on them. I will send you a copy as soon as I could open the tropes.
I have had the report of the Congressional Committee appointed by the last Congress to investigate Chinese matters in California … mee by a Washington print where I spent too much this … Thank you for your kind remembrances.
In the last not of published diplomatic conferences, I read your answer
To the committees questions with deep interest.
Both Sagent and Perley are what people called “politicians”: What they think and say either as Americans or Chinese matters do not carry great weight with the thinking public, though it cannot be denied that they do exercise an influence with the “herds”.
I have great confidence in such … as … and … They mean well and will act as they mean. I think they will do justice to China and the Chinese.
I wonder if it is true that … Olymplants have accepted the agency to furnish the … with Coolies. This is a poor detestable business … … the most favorable circumstances, and I shouldn’t think the Olymplants would allow this fair named to be limited by a traffic that brings nothing but … and degradation to those engaged in it. The him of steamess referred to undoubtedly is for denying coolies
from Hong Kong to Collas. The Spaniards in Peru and fact through all the South Am. States are a degenerate race and … …, … … , proud … … no more fitted to … … with great responsibilities than the savages of the … To expect justice and … treatment from them …, one might so well cast his lot with … … My heart breaks for the poor Chinese who have fallen into the hands of the Spaniards.
Dr. Brown and Hepburn, I am afraid are too old to last very long, this places must be filled by others. I hope this matter will fall in the right men. And how is your own health? And that of Mrs. Williams? I long to see you thereafter, please write me Yung Wing and done with it.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1878-08-23" Title="Letter to Dr. Williams" Page="1">I have conveyed your thanks to the person who brought the roll for Mr. Van Names.
Mr. Chin wishes me to thank you for your kind wishes and to … the hope that you are in good health.
Wing Shing holds a very … … in the embassy. He is head interpreter and translator to the … in Washington. He has … three sums to be selected. I have located them.
I love … yet read the
List the … … with China and cannot … you reliable information reflecting this point of inquiry. It is not yet determined when Chin will head for Madrid – very likely some time next Spring.
I am very sorry that the … Olymphant … … everything to do with Chuius … but think that they have …
Then prestige and food, name by accepting the Agency for Chuius … from the … food.
The agency … the must favorable … and conducted … the most worthy motives cannot shake itself off from all the … … attached to the … of masses with all its attendant abuses, outrages, and … inhumances. Mr Chun suffered great … that … Olymphant … should even allow themselves to undertake
Such a business.
I will try to send you the exact amt. of contribution passed … my … in my next.
I have succeeded in securing a house for the … in Washington. Please … haste.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1878-05-04" Title="Letter" Page="1">I am much indebted to you for the completion of my set of the … as vol. 13 may be of the greater use to you than to me. I will send it down with the Chinese books that I promised you sometime ago.
I find that I have rushed the original list. Mr. Chuius books set apart for you and as I like to look this was before sending them down. May I … you to send me your list. The number of the … have been using some of the books
Show misplaced them.
I saw the … request to you in the … I hope it will soon be made available.
In addition to the books to be sent sometime next wek, I hope another to China, for a … … “…” and my the “collection of students Mr Ta Tching … and also a … of the “…” … for Yale College.
</text>
    <text Source="Yale University Library" Date="1879-03-26" Title="Letter to Addison Van Name" Page="1">I send herewith bill of … for another … of … books the … addition of the “complete collection of statistics of the Ta Tsung Dynasty” in 60 sets – for the … …

P.S. I return to Washington tomorrow.
</text>
  </yung_wing>
</excerpts>
